

CONTACT

- **6** 06 49 85 98 58
- alan@alanrich.dev linkedin.com/in/alanrich-dev
- 56 Rue Riquet 31000, Toulouse France

COMPETENCIES

- Programming Languages
 - Javascript/Typescript
 - CSS
 - GraphQL
- Frameworks/Libraries
 - React
 - MUI
 - Redux
 - Next.js
- Testing & QA
 - Jest
 - Cypress E2E
- Development Tools
 - Nx
 - Git
 - NPM
 - Jenkins
- Architecture/System Design
 - Configuration-driven systems
 - Domain Object Modeling

LANGUAGES

- English (Maternal Language)
- Français (B2)

ALAN RICH

FRONT END DEVELOPER

PROFILE

As a front-end developer with five years of professional experience, I have worked extensively maintaining and debugging large-scale, configuration-driven systems. My recent role at Research Innovations Inc. involved resolving complex UI bugs within a framework powered by thousands of configuration files, demonstrating my ability to navigate highly abstracted systems. With an established record of remote work for U.S.-based companies in the national security sector, I bring adaptability, technical proficiency, and a self-driven attitude, capable of delivering results when the stakes are high and success is critical.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Innovations Inc.

2022 - 2024

Software Engineer II

- Used JS, TS, React & MUI to optimize front-end components, ensuring scalability and maintainability within a large Nx monorepo.
- Facilitated interaction between front-end components and underlying data models housed within domain-specific objects that encapsulated both data and business logic.
- Founded and lead a book club for Front End Devs to foster continuous growth and learning.
- Performed daily code reviews, always seeking opportunities to delete code.

OC Tanner

2021 - 2022

Software Engineer

- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to implement user-centric designs, ensuring a smooth and engaging experience for end users.
- Developed intuitive and responsive web interfaces using Javascript and React to optimize the user experience across various devices and screen sizes.
- Utilized GraphQL to efficiently fetch data from APIs, ensuring real-time, dynamic updates and improved performance.

Upwork

2019 - 2021

Front End Developer

- Applied modern ES6+ features and React hooks to simplify state management, enhance reusability, and maintain clean, scalable codebases.
- Integrated RESTful API endpoints to dynamically render data, improving application efficiency and user engagement..

INTERESTS

- Pilates / Running
- Classical Philosophy
- Byzantine History
- Russian Literature
- French Comedy
- Wild Camping
- Minimalism
- Family Life
- Burning Man

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

•	Technical Writer	Upwork	2015 - 2019
•	Research Assistant	Illinois Institute of Technology	2013 - 2014
•	Organic Chemist	Nestle (Chicago)	2012 - 2013
•	Bartender	The Great Canadian Pub (Paris)	2009 - 2011
•	Carpet Merchant	Grand Bazaar (Istanbul)	2009

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (Bac +4)

2005 - 2008

Benedictine University

Thesis: "A One-Pot Asymmetric Robinson Annulation in the Organic Chemistry Majors Laboratory", *Journal of Chemical Education*, 85 (2008)1531-1534, DOI:10.1021/ed085p1531

Cours de Civilisation Française de la Sorbonne

2009 - 2010

Language and French civilisation studies through a program administered by La Fondation Robert de Sorbon and charged with enhancing the influence of French civilisation throughout the world.

Alliance Française de Toulouse

2023

Cours Intensif de Langue Niveau B1

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Burning Man Organization

2015 - 2017

Clean Up Crew: Performed two weeks of environmental remediation, post event, to reduce the impact on the native ecosystem and neighbouring indigenous Native American communities.

Amateur Athletic Union (AAU)

2012 - 2014

Basketball Coach: Assisted with coaching a youth summer league basketball team for high school students in Chicago.